Register of the Milton Friedman papers 77011.4088897
Hoover Institution Archives
Milton Friedman papers
1931-2006
Hoover Institution Archives
Friedman, Milton, 1912-2006
Friedman, Rose D.
77011.4088897
97.8 linear feet 227 manuscript boxes, 4 oversize boxes, 4 card file boxes, 1 slide box, 1 envelope
Speeches and writings, correspondence, notes, statistics, printed matter, sound recordings, videotapes, and photographs relating to economic theory, economic conditions in the United States, and governmental economic policy. Digitized copies of many of the sound and video recordings in this collection, as well as some of Friedman's writings, are available at https://miltonfriedman.hoover.org.
Box 112
Shelf 141.06
Box 114-234
Shelf 257
Box 1-109
Shelf 14.38/45
Microfilm shelf 1
Shelf 16.139
Box 110
Shelf 123.05
Photo file
Box 113
Shelf 8.05
Microfilm shelf 2
Shelf 16.170.
Box 111
Shelf 14.11
Box 235-236
Shelf 270
Access
Boxes 103-107 and 235-236 closed. Digital use copies available. The remainder of the collection is open for research. Digitized copies of many of the sound and video recordings in this collection, as well as some of Friedman's writings, are available at https://miltonfriedman.hoover.org.
Use copies of some sound and video recordings in this collection are available for immediate access. To access other sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
First acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1977, the collection includes additions from the 1980s until 2007 in boxes 109-112 and a large increment in boxes 113-235 acquired in 2008.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (226 reels). Digitized copies of many of the sound and video recordings in this collection, as well as some of Friedman's writings, are available at https://miltonfriedman.hoover.org.
Related Collections
Collected Works of Milton Friedman website, http://miltonfriedman.hoover.org Collected Works of Milton Friedman Project records, Hoover Institution Archives The Legacy of Milton and Rose Friedman's Free to Choose conference proceedings, 2003, Hoover Institution Archives Free to Choose: video tape, 1980, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
1912 July 31 Born, Brooklyn, New York
1932 B.A., Rutgers University
1933 M.A., University of Chicago
1934-1935 Research assistant, Social Science Research Committee, University of Chicago
1935-1937 Associate economist, National Resources Committee, Washington, D.C.
1937-1940 Lecturer, Columbia University
1937-1946, 1948-1981 Member, Research Staff, National Bureau of Economic Research, New York
1938 Married Rose Director
1940-1941 Visiting professor of economics, University of Wisconsin
1941-1943 Principal economist, Division of Tax Research, U.S. Treasury Department
1942 Professor, United States Department of Agriculture Graduate School, Washington, D.C.
1943 Author (with Carl S. Shoup and Ruth P. Mack), Taxing to Prevent Inflation
1943-1945 Associate director, Statistical Research Group, Division of War Research, Columbia University
1945 Author (with Simon S. Kuznets), Income from Independent Professional Practice
1945-1946 Associate professor of economics and statistics, University of Minnesota
1946 Ph.D., Columbia University
1946-1948 Associate professor of economics, University of Chicago
1948 Author (with Harold A. Freeman, Frederic Mosteller, W. Allen Wallis), Sampling Inspection
1948-1982 Professor of economics, University of Chicago
1950 Consultant, Economic Cooperation Administration, Office of the United States Special Representative in Europe, Paris
1953 Author, Essays in Positive Economics
1956-1979 Council of Academic Advisers, American Enterprise Institute
1957 Author, A Theory of the Consumption Function
1960 Author, A Program for Monetary Stability
1962 Author, Price Theory: A Provisional Text Author (with Rose D. Friedman), Capitalism and Freedom
1963 Author (with Anna J. Schwartz), A Monetary History of the United States, 1867-1960 Author, Inflation: Causes and Consequences
1968 Author, Dollars and Deficits: Inflation, Monetary Policy and the Balance of Payments
1968-1994 Advisory Board, Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking
1969 Author, The Optimum Quantity of Money and Other Essays
1969-1970 Member, The President's Commission on an All-Volunteer Armed Force
1970 Author (with Anna J. Schwartz), Monetary Statistics of the United States
1972 Author, An Economist's Protest: Columns on Political Economy
1973 Member, The President's Commission on White House Fellows
1975 Author, There Is no Such Thing as a Free Lunch
1976 Author, Price Theory Recipient, Nobel Prize in Economics
1977- Senior research fellow, Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, Stanford University, California
1978 Author, Tax Limitation, Inflation and the Role of Government
1980 Author (with Rose D. Friedman), Free to Choose, and presenter of a ten-part TV series on PBS of the same title.
1981-1988 Member, The President's Economic Policy Advisory Board
1982 Author (with Anna J. Schwartz), Monetary Trends in the U.S. and the United Kingdom
1983 Author, Bright Promises, Dismal Performance: An Economist's Protest
1983- Professor emeritus, University of Chicago
1984 Author (with Rose D. Friedman), Tyranny of the Status Quo, and presenter of a three part PBS television program of the same title.
1986 Awarded the Grand Cordon of the First Class Order of the Sacred Treasure (Japanese Government)
1988 Awarded the National Medal of Science Awarded the Presidential Medal of Freedom
1992 Author, Money Mischief: Episodes in Monetary History Author (with Thomas S. Szasz), edited and with a preface by Arnold S. Trebach and Kevin B. Zeese, Friedman and Szasz on Liberty and Drugs: Essays on the Free Market and Prohibition
1992- Active Member, Academia Scientiarum et Artium Europaea (European Academy of Sciences and Arts)
1993- Founding Member, National Coalition for Drug Policy Change
1996- Chairman, Board of Directors, Milton and Rose D. Friedman Foundation to promote public understanding of the need for major reform in K-12 education and the role that competition through educational choice can play in achieving that reform
1998 Author (with Rose D. Friedman) Two Lucky People: Memoirs
1999- Member, Advisory Board, California Parents for Educational Choice
2006 Died
1912 July 31 Born, Brooklyn, New York
1932 B.A., Rutgers University
1933 M.A., University of Chicago
1934-1935 Research assistant, Social Science Research Committee, University of Chicago
1935-1937 Associate economist, National Resources Committee, Washington, D.C.
1937-1940 Lecturer, Columbia University
1937-1946, 1948-1981 Member, Research Staff, National Bureau of Economic Research, New York
1938 Married Rose Director
1940-1941 Visiting professor of economics, University of Wisconsin
1941-1943 Principal economist, Division of Tax Research, U.S. Treasury Department
1942 Professor, United States Department of Agriculture Graduate School, Washington, D.C.
1943 Author (with Carl S. Shoup and Ruth P. Mack), Taxing to Prevent Inflation
1943-1945 Associate director, Statistical Research Group, Division of War Research, Columbia University
1945 Author (with Simon S. Kuznets), Income from Independent Professional Practice
1945-1946 Associate professor of economics and statistics, University of Minnesota
1946 Ph.D., Columbia University
1946-1948 Associate professor of economics, University of Chicago
1948 Author (with Harold A. Freeman, Frederic Mosteller, W. Allen Wallis), Sampling Inspection
1948-1982 Professor of economics, University of Chicago
1950 Consultant, Economic Cooperation Administration, Office of the United States Special Representative in Europe, Paris
1953 Author, Essays in Positive Economics
1956-1979 Council of Academic Advisers, American Enterprise Institute
1957 Author, A Theory of the Consumption Function
1960 Author, A Program for Monetary Stability
1962 Author, Price Theory: A Provisional Text Author (with Rose D. Friedman), Capitalism and Freedom
1963 Author (with Anna J. Schwartz), A Monetary History of the United States, 1867-1960 Author, Inflation: Causes and Consequences
1968 Author, Dollars and Deficits: Inflation, Monetary Policy and the Balance of Payments
1968-1994 Advisory Board, Journal of Money, Credit, and Banking
1969 Author, The Optimum Quantity of Money and Other Essays
1969-1970 Member, The President's Commission on an All-Volunteer Armed Force
1970 Author (with Anna J. Schwartz), Monetary Statistics of the United States
1972 Author, An Economist's Protest: Columns on Political Economy
1973 Member, The President's Commission on White House Fellows
1975 Author, There Is no Such Thing as a Free Lunch
1976 Author, Price Theory Recipient, Nobel Prize in Economics
1977- Senior research fellow, Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace, Stanford University, California
1978 Author, Tax Limitation, Inflation and the Role of Government
1980 Author (with Rose D. Friedman), Free to Choose, and presenter of a ten-part TV series on PBS of the same title.
1981-1988 Member, The President's Economic Policy Advisory Board
1982 Author (with Anna J. Schwartz), Monetary Trends in the U.S. and the United Kingdom
1983 Author, Bright Promises, Dismal Performance: An Economist's Protest
1983- Professor emeritus, University of Chicago
1984 Author (with Rose D. Friedman), Tyranny of the Status Quo, and presenter of a three part PBS television program of the same title.
1986 Awarded the Grand Cordon of the First Class Order of the Sacred Treasure (Japanese Government)
1988 Awarded the National Medal of Science Awarded the Presidential Medal of Freedom
1992 Author, Money Mischief: Episodes in Monetary History Author (with Thomas S. Szasz), edited and with a preface by Arnold S. Trebach and Kevin B. Zeese, Friedman and Szasz on Liberty and Drugs: Essays on the Free Market and Prohibition
1992- Active Member, Academia Scientiarum et Artium Europaea (European Academy of Sciences and Arts)
1993- Founding Member, National Coalition for Drug Policy Change
1996- Chairman, Board of Directors, Milton and Rose D. Friedman Foundation to promote public understanding of the need for major reform in K-12 education and the role that competition through educational choice can play in achieving that reform
1998 Author (with Rose D. Friedman) Two Lucky People: Memoirs
1999- Member, Advisory Board, California Parents for Educational Choice
2006 Died
Scope and Content of Collection
The Milton Friedman papers include a variety of materials relating to economic theory, economic conditions in the United States, and governmental economic policy. Friedman interacted with a wide network of academics, economists, and politicians, with whom he corresponded frequently. The papers display his thoughts and expertise in extensive correspondence, speeches and writings, collected research materials, statistics, printed materials, and photographs, as well as sound and video recordings.
Audiotapes.; Economics.; Economists.; Free enterprise.; United States--Economic conditions.; United States--Economic policy.; Video tapes.; Friedman, Milton, 1912-2006; Friedman, Rose D.; Reagan, Ronald.
- Biographical File, 1931-1980 (Boxes 1-5)
  Scope and Contents note
  Articles, clippings, awards, bibliographies, biographies, school and employment records, and resolutions, arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Articles and clippings on Milton Friedman
    - 1950-1963 (Box-folder 1: 1)
    - 1963-1969 (Box-folder 1: 2)
    - 1964 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    - 1965-1966 (Box-folder 1: 4)
    - 1967 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    - 1968 (Box-folder 1: 6)
    - 1969 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    - 1970 (Box-folder 2: 2)
    - 1970-1972 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    - 1971 (Box-folder 2: 4)
    - 1972-1973 (Box-folder 2: 5)
    - 1973-1974 (Box-folder 2: 6)
    - 1974-1976 (Box-folder 3: 1)
    - 1975-1976 (Box-folder 3: 2)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 3: 3)
    - 1977 (Box-folder 4: 1-2)
    - 1978 (Box-folder 4: 3)
    - 1978-1980 (Box-folder 4: 4)
    - 1979 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - Awards (Box-folder 5: 1)
  - Bibliographies (Box-folder 5: 2)
  - Biographies (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Employment records
    - Civil Service Commission, 1936-1940 (Box-folder 5: 4)
    - Department of Commerce, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 5: 5)
    - University of Chicago, 1946-1966 (Box-folder 5: 6)
      Includes financial records.
    - Economic Cooperation Administration, 1951 (Box-folder 5: 7)
    - Council of Economic Advisers, 1969-1975 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Resolutions honoring Milton Friedman (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Subject file
    - Health (Box-folder 5: 10)
    - Student years (Box-folder 5: 11-13)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 5: 14)
- Correspondence, 1940-1991 (Boxes 6-35)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - General
    - Autograph requests (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Congratulatory messages on Nobel Prize, 1976
      - Unidentified (Box-folder 6: 2)
      - A-B (Box-folder 6: 3)
      - C-D (Box-folder 6: 4)
      - E-F (Box-folder 6: 5)
      - G-H (Box-folder 6: 6)
      - I-K (Box-folder 6: 7)
      - L-M (Box-folder 6: 8)
      - N-Q (Box-folder 6: 9)
      - R-S (Box-folder 7: 1)
      - T-V (Box-folder 7: 2)
      - W-Z (Box-folder 7: 3)
    - Recommendation letters
      - 1946-1949 (Box-folder 7: 4)
      - 1950-1954 (Box-folder 7: 5)
      - 1956 (Box-folder 7: 6)
      - 1958-1979 (Box-folder 7: 7)
    - Viewers' comments on Milton Friedman's appearances on the Phil Donahue Show
      - 1979 (Box-folder 8: 1-2)
      - 1980-1981 (Box-folder 8: 3-5)
    - Aar-Adl (Box-folder 9: 1)
    - Afs-Alv (Box-folder 9: 2)
    - Ame-Ande (Box-folder 9: 3)
    - Ando-Arm (Box-folder 9: 4)
    - Arn-Att (Box-folder 9: 5)
    - Aug-Avr (Box-folder 9: 6)
    - Baa-Bak (Box-folder 9: 7)
    - Bal-Bar (Box-folder 9: 8)
    - Bas-Bax (Box-folder 9: 9)
    - Bea-Belk (Box-folder 9: 10)
    - Bell-Bey (Box-folder 9: 11)
    - Bha-Bjo (Box-folder 10: 1)
    - Bla-Blu (Box-folder 10: 2)
    - Boa-Bop (Box-folder 10: 3)
    - Bor-Boy (Box-folder 10: 4)
    - Bra (Box-folder 10: 5)
    - Bre-Bri (Box-folder 10: 6)
    - Bro (Box-folder 10: 7)
    - Bru-Buro (Box-folder 10: 8)
    - Burt-Bz (Box-folder 10: 9)
    - Cal-Cap (Box-folder 11: 1)
    - Car-Cav (Box-folder 11: 2)
    - Ce-Cha (Box-folder 11: 3)
    - Che-Chu (Box-folder 11: 4)
    - Ci-Cl (Box-folder 11: 5)
    - Coa-Coi (Box-folder 11: 6)
    - Col (Box-folder 11: 7)
    - Com-Coo (Box-folder 11: 8)
    - Cop-Coy (Box-folder 12: 1)
    - Cr (Box-folder 12: 2)
    - Cu (Box-folder 12: 3)
    - Daa-Dar (Box-folder 12: 4)
    - Das-Dav (Box-folder 12: 5)
    - De-Di (Box-folder 12: 6)
    - Doe-Dwo (Box-folder 12: 7)
    - Ear-Ext (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - Fal-Fou (Box-folder 13: 2)
    - Fra-Fur (Box-folder 13: 3)
    - Gaf-Gir (Box-folder 13: 4)
    - Gla-Gwi (Box-folder 13: 5)
    - Had-Hay (Box-folder 13: 6)
    - Hea-Hit (Box-folder 13: 7)
    - Hof-Hyn (Box-folder 13: 8)
    - Ind-Iwa (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - Jac-Jen (Box-folder 14: 2)
    - Joh-Jou (Box-folder 14: 3)
    - Kah-Ket (Box-folder 14: 4)
    - Kha-Kut (Box-folder 14: 5)
    - Lak-Lew (Box-folder 14: 6)
    - Lic-Lue (Box-folder 14: 7)
    - Mac-May (Box-folder 14: 8)
    - McB-McP (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - Mea-Mey (Box-folder 15: 2)
    - Mic-Miy (Box-folder 15: 3)
    - Moa-Mye (Box-folder 15: 4)
    - Nar-Ney (Box-folder 15: 5)
    - Nic-Noy (Box-folder 15: 6)
    - Oba-Opi (Box-folder 15: 7)
    - Pad-Pay (Box-folder 15: 8)
    - Pea-Ple (Box-folder 15: 9)
    - Pol-Put (Box-folder 15: 10)
    - Quic-Quin (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - Rad-Rey (Box-folder 16: 2)
    - Ric-Roy (Box-folder 16: 3)
    - Rud-Rut (Box-folder 16: 4)
    - Sae-Scu (Box-folder 16: 5)
    - Seg-Sho (Box-folder 16: 6)
    - Sid-Slo (Box-folder 16: 7)
    - Smi-Sny (Box-folder 16: 8)
    - Soa-Spr (Box-folder 16: 9)
    - Sta-Sti (Box-folder 16: 10)
    - Sto-Swe (Box-folder 17: 1)
    - Taf-Tix (Box-folder 17: 2)
    - Tol-Tys (Box-folder 17: 3)
    - Udi-Urq (Box-folder 17: 4)
    - Val-Vuc (Box-folder 17: 5)
    - Wad-Wat (Box-folder 17: 6)
    - Web-Whi (Box-folder 17: 7)
    - Wie-Wis (Box-folder 17: 8)
    - Wol-Wri (Box-folder 17: 9)
    - Yam-Zoe (Box-folder 17: 10)
  - Abdel-Salam, Osman Hashim, 1972 (Box-folder 18: 1)
  - Ablin, Richard, 1970-1977 (Box-folder 18: 2)
  - Abrahams, Martin, 1956 (Box-folder 18: 3)
  - Abram, Morris B., Jr., 1970-1973 (Box-folder 18: 4)
  - Abramovitz, Moses [See also: Stanford University], 1947-1978. (Box-folder 18: 5)
  - Abt, Clark C., 1973-1976 (Box-folder 18: 6)
  - Accademia Nazionale dei Lincei, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 18: 7)
  - Adams, Brock, 1976 (Box-folder 18: 8)
  - Adams, Charles, 1964 (Box-folder 18: 9)
  - Adams, E. Sherman, 1953-1960 (Box-folder 18: 10)
  - Adar, Zvi (and Noel M. Edelson), 1975-1976 (Box-folder 18: 11)
  - Adelman, Abram E., 1968-1969 (Box-folder 18: 12)
  - Adickes, Roland, 1967 (Box-folder 18: 13)
  - Adie, Douglas K., 1964-1978 (Box-folder 18: 14)
  - Advisory Committee on Intergovernmental Relations, 1979 (Box-folder 18: 15)
  - Agarwala, Ramgopal, 1964-1972 (Box-folder 18: 16)
  - Akerman, Johan, 1954-1962 (Box-folder 18: 17)
  - Alchian, Armen, 1948-1977 (Box-folder 18: 18)
  - Aldine Publishing Company, 1966 (Box-folder 18: 19)
  - Aliber, Robert Z. (Committee for Economic Development), 1964 (Box-folder 18: 20)
  - Allais, Maurice, 1948-1978 (Box-folder 18: 21)
  - Allen, Carl E., 1959-1960 (Box-folder 18: 22)
  - Allen, J. Garrott, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 18: 23)
  - Allen, Richard V., 1968 (Box-folder 18: 24)
  - Allen, S. Troy, 1967-1976 (Box-folder 18: 25)
  - Allen, Steve, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 18: 26)
  - Allen, William R., 1957-1978 (Box-folder 18: 27)
  - Almonacid, Ruben D., 1969-1974 (Box-folder 18: 28)
  - Alon, Gabriel, 1953-1969 (Box-folder 18: 29)
  - American Economic Association (Morris A. Copeland, Calvin B. Hoover, Theodore W. Schultz), 1953-1966 (Box-folder 19: 1)
  - American Economic Review (John G. Gurley, Paul T. Homan), 1950-1966 (Box-folder 19: 2)
  - American Enterprise Institute, 1972 (Box-folder 19: 3)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1960 (Box-folder 19: 4)
  - American Statistical Association (Merrill M. Flood), 1948-1949 (Box-folder 19: 5)
  - Ames, Bruce N., 1978-1979 (Box-folder 19: 6)
  - Amin, R. K., 1963 (Box-folder 19: 7)
  - Amnesty International, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 19: 8)
  - Andersen, Leonall C., 1965-1978 (Box-folder 19: 9)
  - Anderson, C. W. (Employers' Association of Milwaukee), 1959-1977 (Box-folder 19: 10)
  - Anderson, David G., 1966-1968 (Box-folder 19: 11)
  - Anderson, Martin, 1965-1979 (Box-folder 19: 12)
  - Anderson, Paul S., 1961-1962 (Box-folder 19: 13)
  - Anderson, Robert O., 1978 (Box-folder 19: 14)
  - Anderson, T. W., 1959 (Box-folder 19: 15)
  - Anderson, William W., 1963-1966 (Box-folder 19: 16)
  - Andreen, Finn, 1966-1977 (Box-folder 19: 17)
  - Angel, Ronald W., 1977-1978 (Box-folder 19: 18)
  - Applegate, Albert A., 1966 (Box-folder 19: 19)
  - Arbuckle, Ernest C., 1958-1977 (Box-folder 19: 20)
  - Argy, Victor, 1969 (Box-folder 19: 21)
  - Arnoldy, Roman F., 1974-1979 (Box-folder 19: 22)
  - Arrow, Kenneth J., 1951-1973 (Box-folder 19: 23)
  - Atlas, S., undated (Box-folder 19: 24)
  - Atlee, John S., 1956 (Box-folder 19: 25)
  - Atrill, Verne H., 1950-1956 (Box-folder 19: 26)
  - Audouin, Raoul, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 19: 27)
  - Auerbach, Robert D., 1968-1979 (Box-folder 19: 28)
  - Auernheimer, Leonardo, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 19: 29)
  - Australian Financial Review, 1978 (Box-folder 19: 30)
  - Axelrad, Norman, 1978 (Box-folder 19: 31)
  - Axilrod, Stephen H., 1960-1969 (Box-folder 19: 32)
  - Ayau, Manuel F., 1974-1978 (Box-folder 19: 33)
  - Aydt, Arthur E., 1969 (Box-folder 19: 34)
  - Bach, G. L., 1946-1977 (Box-folder 20: 1)
  - Baer, John W., 1978-1979 (Box-folder 20: 2)
  - Bagley, Edward R., 1973-1975 (Box-folder 20: 3)
  - Bailey, Martin J., 1972 (Box-folder 20: 4)
  - Baily, Nathan A., 1970-1976 (Box-folder 20: 5)
  - Bain, James K., 1975-1976 (Box-folder 20: 6)
  - Bajt, Aleksander, 1973 (Box-folder 20: 7)
  - Bakal, Richard, 1964 (Box-folder 20: 8)
  - Bakar, Gerson, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 20: 9)
  - Ball, George W., 1969 (Box-folder 20: 10)
  - Banfield, Edward C., 1970-1978 (Box-folder 20: 11)
  - Barclay, Clifford H., 1977-1979 (Box-folder 20: 12)
  - Barger, Harold, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 20: 13)
  - Barkai, Haim, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 20: 14)
  - Barker, C. Austin, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 20: 15)
  - Barnard, Doug, Jr., 1979 (Box-folder 20: 16)
  - Baroody, William J., 1963-1973 (Box-folder 20: 17)
  - Barr, Joseph W., 1961 (Box-folder 20: 18)
  - Barr, Nicholas A., 1980 (Box-folder 20: 19)
  - Barro, Robert J., 1969-1978 (Box-folder 20: 20)
  - Barrows, Perce S., 1968-1969 (Box-folder 20: 21)
  - Bartley, Robert L. (Wall Street Journal), 1975-1979 (Box-folder 20: 22)
  - Barton, Charles T., 1974-1977 (Box-folder 20: 23)
  - Bar-Yosef, Y., 1974-1977 (Box-folder 20: 24)
  - Bass, Henry, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 20: 25)
  - Bassett, Marjorie, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 20: 26)
  - Bauer, Peter T., 1953-1979 (Box-folder 20: 27)
  - Baumol, William J., 1949-1975 (Box-folder 20: 28)
  - Beadle, George W., 1964-1967 (Box-folder 20: 29)
  - Becker, Gary S., 1953-1983 (Box-folder 20: 30)
  - Beer, Gerald, 1974 (Box-folder 20: 31)
  - Beham, Yohanan, 1969-1977 (Box-folder 20: 32)
  - Beichman, Arnold, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 20: 33)
  - Bell, Carolyn Shaw, 1973 (Box-folder 20: 34)
  - Bell, Geoffrey L., 1964-1969 (Box-folder 20: 35)
  - Bell, James W., 1948-1959 (Box-folder 20: 36)
  - Ben-David, Joseph, 1958-1970 (Box-folder 20: 37)
  - Benishay, Haskell, 1961-1972 (Box-folder 20: 38)
  - Bennett, John T., Jr., 1975 (Box-folder 20: 39)
  - Benston, George J., 1965-1969 (Box-folder 20: 40)
  - Berelson, Bernard, 1955-1977 (Box-folder 20: 41)
  - Bernstein, Edward M., 1965-1975 (Box-folder 20: 42)
  - Bernstein, Joel, 1951-1976 (Box-folder 20: 43)
  - Bernstein, Peter L., 1967-1977 (Box-folder 20: 44)
  - Berry, D., 1952 (Box-folder 20: 45)
  - Bierly, Ivan R., 1957-1963 (Box-folder 20: 46)
  - Birenbaum, William, 1948-1955 (Box-folder 20: 47)
  - Birkenhead, T. Bruce, 1966 (Box-folder 20: 48)
  - Birnbaum, Eugene A., 1970-1978 (Box-folder 20: 49)
  - Black, Fischer, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 20: 50)
  - Black, John D., 1955 (Box-folder 20: 51)
  - Blackie, William, 1973-1979 (Box-folder 20: 52)
  - Blake, Jacqueline, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 20: 53)
  - Blatchford, Frank W., III, 1961 (Box-folder 20: 54)
  - Blough, Roy, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 20: 55)
  - Bluefarb, Sam, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 20: 56)
  - Blumberg, Aryeh, 1964-1979 (Box-folder 20: 57)
  - Boarman, Patrick M., 1965-1967 (Box-folder 21: 1)
  - Boddy, Francis M., 1949-1956 (Box-folder 21: 2)
  - Bodenhorn, Diran, 1951-1963 (Box-folder 21: 3)
  - Bodkin, Ronald, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 21: 4)
  - Body, Zvi, 1975 (Box-folder 21: 5)
  - Boggs, Danny J., 1968-1969 (Box-folder 21: 6)
  - Boorstin, Daniel J., 1973 (Box-folder 21: 7)
  - Booth, Wayne C., 1971 (Box-folder 21: 8)
  - Bordo, Michael David, 1968-1978 (Box-folder 21: 9)
  - Borts, George H., 1952-1973 (Box-folder 21: 10)
  - Boschwitz, Rudy, 1979 (Box-folder 21: 11)
  - Boskin, Michael (and John Shoven), 1974 (Box-folder 21: 12)
  - Bossons, John (and Thomas Wilson), 1964-1974 (Box-folder 21: 13)
  - Bowden, Lord Vivian, 1974 (Box-folder 21: 14)